This is my third time time taking photos for the homepage.
ホームページ用の写真撮影もこれで三回目
I've come to Nonhoi Park, a zoo and botanical garden in Toyohashi City.
俺は豊橋市の動植物園
The model for today's photo shoot is...
今回の撮影モデルは…
Nukkun! Look! An elephant!
ぬっくん！ほら象いるよ！なんかこう！
There's tons of them! There's lots of them!
めっちゃいる！たくさんいる！
Yeah, there sure are.
ああ、たくさんいるな
Yes, this low IQ feeling.
そうこのIQ低めな感じ
It's Yakishio.
焼塩だ
Yakishio, don't lean over the railing like that!
焼塩、手摺から体乗り出すなって
Wouldn't it be better to get a little closer?
少しでも近いほうが良くない？
I wonder if we can go into the pond where the elephants are bathing?
象が水浴びしてる池のとこ 入っていいのかな?
No, we can't.
ダメだぞ
Rather, why did you think it'd be okay?
むしろどうしていいと思った？
I see...
そっか…
Well, let's take the photo.
じゃ 写真撮って
Here, I'll pose.
はい ポーズ
Okay, I'm taking it.
はい 撮ります
(Yakishio) Did you take it? Show me, show me!
撮れた？見せて見せて
Uhm...
えっと…
Maybe something like this?
こんな感じかな
You got a good shot, didn't you?
よく撮れてんじゃん
Then, I guess the photo shoot is done, right?
じゃあこれで撮影は終わりだね
Right...
ああ…
What's wrong, Nukkun?
どうしたの、ぬっくん？
You're right that this photo is good.
この写真は確かにいい
But Yakishio...
だけど焼塩
Don't you want to...
もっと上を…
Aim a much higher?
目指したくならないか？
Higher?
上？
Yeah.
ああ
At this rate, the photos of Yanami eating will be the only ones at the top of the homepage.
このままでは八奈見さんが 食ってるだけの写真が
It'll be the only photo that shows the whole world the Literature Club and Toyohashi City.
全世界に ツワブキ高校文芸部と豊橋市をアピールする一枚だ
Is that really fine?
それでいいのか？
No, it isn't!
いや、良くない！
If its you, we can aim higher!
焼塩ならもっと上を目指せる
That's what I think.
そんな気がするんだ
Oh...
おお
I don't really get it, but...
よくわかんないけど
Nukkun, you're really motivated.
ぬっくんやる気だね
Alright, I'm in!
いいよ その話乗った！
Okay.
よし
Well, why don't we take a full tour of the zoo?
じゃあ動物園を一通り回ろうか？
Yakishio, where do you want to go?
焼塩 どこ行きたい？
Let's go see the monkeys then, the monkeys.
じゃあ猿行こうよ 猿
Uhm...
えっと
The monkey area is here...
モンキーエリアこっちだな
But Nukkun, why are you so motivated?
でもぬっくんなんでそんなにやる気なの？
You always just rush through things and try to go home right away.
いつも適当に済ませて すぐ帰ろうとするじゃん
Uh... Well... I guess...
ええ…ああ…まあ…
This is the real me.
これが本当の俺なんだって
Hmm...
へー
That sounds like a lie...
ちょっと噓っぽいな
Are you hiding something from me?
なんかあたしに隠してない？
Huh?!
へっ！？
No...
いや…
It's a joke, it's a joke.
ハハハ 冗談 冗談
That's right.
そう
For the other photoshoots, I've had to be overly cautious.
これまでの撮影は やたら気を遣うばかりだった
But taking photos of the Literature Club girls from a distance like this...
しかし文芸部ガールの連中は
Okay! Nukkun, lets get going!
よーし ぬっくん 早く行くよ！
Ah, Yakishio, don't run!
ああ 焼塩 走るなって
...is kinda fun.
なんかちょっと楽しいのだ
Oh, there are the monkeys.
おお 猿いるね 猿
Yakishio, you like monkeys?
焼塩 猿好きなんだ
If anything, I'd say they are enemies.
どっちかっていうと敵かな
I need to get even.
リベンジしたくてさ
Huh?
へ？
Do you have something against monkeys?
猿になんか恨みでもあるのか？
When I was little...
ちっちゃなころ
I went to a zoo with free-ranging lemurs.
キツネザルが放し飼いになってる 動物園に行ってね
While feeding them, one stole my hat.
餌やりしてたら 帽子取られたことがあったんだ
That must have been rough.
それは災難だったな
Right?
でしょ？
I climbed up a tree to chase after it, but the branch broke.
木の上に逃げたから 上って追いかけたら枝が折れてさ
I fell into a pond, and it was a whole thing!
池に落ちて大騒ぎになったの
Eh.
ええ
Were you alright?
大丈夫だったのか？
Yeah, I got it back.
うん ちゃんと取り返したよ
You were fine, hih?
平気だったんだな
Since then, I've really wanted to settle things with lemurs.
それでキツネザルとは ちゃんと決着つけたくてさ
No, the zoos are different.
いや動物園が違うし
They're not even the same species.
そもそも別個体だろ
Aren't their faces the same?
顔は同じじゃん？
Is there a way we can get into the enclosure?
どっかから網の中に入れないかな？
Can you win without doing that?
そのまま勝ってもらえ
If you do that, they won't just let us off with a scolding.
そんなことしたら
Let's take a photo with those monkeys in the background.
さあ あそこの猿をバックに写真撮ろう
Sure...
おお…
Okay. Like this?
はい こんな感じ？
Yeah, that looks great.
ああ いい感じだ
Next, why not try a slightly more "ennui" expression?
次はちょっと アンニュイな表情をしてみようか？
"Ennui?"
アンニュイ？
Like this?
こう？
Oh, that's good.
おお それいいな
Yeah, really good.
うん いいぞ
If we do this, the monkey is getting in the way...
こうなると バックの猿邪魔だな
What are you mumbling about?
何ブツブツ言ってんのさ？
The photo?
撮れた？
It looks perfect.
バッチリだ
Yakishio, I didn't know you could make that kind of face.
焼塩 あんな表情できたんだな
I just remembered when my teeth hurt.
歯が痛い時思い出してみたの
That's what "ennui" feels like, right?
アンニュイってそんな感じでしょう？
Uhm...
えっと
If its you, then yes.
焼塩ならそうだな
Alright!
よし！
Let's see the lions next!
次はライオン行こう！
Hey, I told you not to run!
ああ だから走るなって！
Oh, lions are strong, aren't they?
おーやっぱライオン強そうだね
It seems like it'll be hard to aim for the throats of the males.
オスは喉元狙うの難しそうだな
Please don't fight them.
絶対に戦うなよ
I'm not joking, okay?
ふりじゃないからな
Nukkun, I'm a high schooler, you know.
ぬっくん あたしも高校生だよ
I know I won't be able to win bare handed.
素手じゃ 勝てないことくらいわかってるって
Okay, if you get it...
ああ 分かってるなら…
...Bare handed?
…素手？
If I get one good shot in, I think I can win.
ワンチャンやりが あれば勝てると思うんだよ
I have a 30% win rate during image training.
イメージトレーニングでは 勝利3割くらいだし
You're really winning, huh...
結構勝ってるな
But I can't see myself winning against a hippo.
でもカバに 勝てるイメージが湧かないんだよね
Do you think it'd be better to use my bare hands?
あれかな？ いっそ素手の方がいいのかな？
Stick to battling something like a Shiba Inu.
戦うのは柴犬くらいにしておけ
I won't fight dogs.
犬とは戦わないよ
They're cute and always show their bellies.
すぐにお腹見せてきて 可愛いじゃん
They really bark at me though...
俺 犬にめっちゃ吠えられるんだけど
Like Chihuahuas...
チワワとか
Really?
そう？
Chiuahuas have this trembling image to them, don't they?
チワワって プルプル触れてるイメージかな
Even the Kishu Ken at my relative's turns over when I get close.
親戚んとこの紀州犬も 私が近づくと伏せするし
Animals understand when someone is stronger than they are, right?
動物って 自分より強い奴が分かるんだな
In other words, do Chihuahuas think they're stronger than me?
つまり俺 チワワになめられてるのか
Okay, then. why not take a photo?
ええ じゃあ 写真撮ろうか？
Stand over there.
はいそこ立って
(Yakishio) Okay!
はーい
Like this?
こんな感じ？
Yakishio really is photogenic, huh...
やっぱ 焼塩の立ち姿は絵になるな
Yanami.
八奈見よ
This is what it means to be "grammable."
これが本当の映えというやつだ
Yeah, it looks good.
うん いい感じだ
As expected of Yakishio.
さすが焼塩だな
Alright, let's go see the tiger next.
よし じゃあ次は虎行こう
We need to confirm if they're stronger than lions.
ライオンと どっちが強いか確認しないと
When you say "confirm..."
確認って
You didn't just imagine yourself fighting a lion, right?
まさか今 イメージでライオンと戦ってたのか？
Yes, and it was a draw.
うん 相打ちだったよ
From now, I'll avoid going against Yakishio.
今後焼塩には逆らわないようにしよう
Huh.
あれ
The tigers are next to the monkeys, aren't they?
そういえば虎って 猿の隣だろう？
Wouldn't it have been better to go there first?
ライオンより 先に行けばよかったのに
We won't be able to get our steps in if we do that.
それじゃ距離を稼げないじゃん
And it's always good to do lots of running.
たくさん走った方が得でしょう
Is it?
そうかな
Isn't it bad?
損してない？
You'll get it if you run.
走ればわかるって
Alright, Nukkun, let's get going!
はい 行くぬっくん！
Don't pull me!
だから引っ張るなって！
Are you okay, Nukkun?
大丈夫ぬっくん？
Here, Oolong tea.
はい ウーロン茶
Th-thank you...
あ…ありがとう
We're at an open café on the first floor of the observation tower.
俺たちがいるのは
Yakishio brought me here since I was completely exhausted from running.
走り回って完全にばてた俺を
By the way, I ran all the way here.
ちなみにここまで走ってきた
Are you feeling sick or something?
体調でも悪いの？
That was just a light jog, wasn't it?
軽く走っただけじゃん
That...
あれ…
...was sprinting at full speed to me though...
俺にとっては全力疾走なんだけど
Nukkun, you're too out of shape.
ぬっくん 運動不足だよ
Should I train you?
私がトレーニングしてあげようか？
You?
焼塩が？
Yes.
うん
There's a course where you won't die.
死なない程度に頑張るコースと
And an all-or-nothing course aiming for the top.
一か八かでてっぺん目指すコース
Which do you want?
どちらいい？
Is there one where I don't have to try?
頑張んないコースはない？
Also, one where I won't die.
あと死なないやつ
There isn't
ないよ
I see...
そっか
There isn't...
ないのか
Alright, maybe next time.
じゃあ またの機会に
Oh, what a shame...
ええ 残念…
Well, we've had a break, so let's get going.
よし 休んだし 次行こっか
Where were we going?
他見てないのどこだっけ？
Huh? But, we just finished our break.
え？ まだ休んだばかりなんだけど
Nukkun, humans actually get more tired when sat down.
ぬっくん 人間って座るとかえって疲れるんだよ
If you keep running, it feels really good and all your fatigue goes away.
走り続けてると なんかこういい感じになって疲れとか吹っ飛ぶの
Don't worry, everyone does it.
大丈夫 皆やってるから
Ah, right...
ああ うん
Uhm... we're talking about running right?
えっと そりゃ走る話だよね？
You don't need to say anything if the answer is "no."
答えが「いいえ」の場合は 返事しなくていいから
What else is there?
他に何があるのさ
Let's just circle around this area until we decide where to go!
どこ行くか決まるまで とりあえずこの辺一周！
Then, let's go here! Here, on the map!
じゃあここ行こう！ ほら地図のここ！
The management office...
管理事務所…
Why do you want to go there?
なんでそんなとこ行きたいの？
Huh? Oh, not there.
あれ？ああ違う！
Uhm... here!
えっとこち！
Let's go to the Polar Exhibit.
極地動物館に行こう
The place with polar bears and seals.
北極熊とかアザラシいるとこ
The Polar Exhibit?
極地動物館？
What's wrong, Yakishio?
どうした焼塩？
Nukkun.
ぬっくん
Calm down and listen carefully.
落ち着いてよく聞いて
Okay.
はい
I'll calm down and listen carefully.
落ち着いてよく聞きます
The "kaijuu" here...
ここにいる「カイジュウ」って
[TL Note] 怪獣 (monster) and 海獣 (marine mammal) are both read as "kaijuu."
海の獣って書くんだよ
They aren't the kaijuu that show up in the movies.
特撮に出てくるような 宇宙怪獣はいないからね
Uh, yeah, I knew that...
ああ うん 知ってた
Wait, really?! Since when?
ええ！本当？いつから？
Uhm... I guess it's been since I was a kid?
えっと 物心ついたころからかな
Serious?
マジ？
I didn't know until  middle school!
私 中学生の頃まで 誤解してたよ
I was always on the edge of my seat waiting for the kaijuu to show up!
いつか怪獣が 出てくるかワクワクしてたもん
Middle school...
中学生…
Lemon Yakishio...
焼塩檸檬…
I'm excited to see what she says next!
俺はこいつが 次に何を言い出すか
The Polar Exhibit.
極地動物館
This is where animals from the North and South Pole, like penguins, are kept.
ペンギンなどの北極や南極いる動物が 飼育されている建物だ
(Yakishio) Look, Nukkun! I see something!
ほら ぬっくん！なんかいるよ！
Look, right here.
ほら こっち
Okay, please don't run indoors.
はい 室内で走らない
Oh! They're coming closer!
おー！寄って来たよ！
Is it a fur seal?
オットセイ？
"Spotted seal" is written here.
ゴマフアザラシって書いてあるじゃん？
Look, "seal."
アザラシだって
Is it different from a fur seal?
オットセイと違うの？
See, fur seals have that black, oily look, don't they?
ほら
Is that different from a sea lion?
それってアシカとは違うの？
Hmm... the difference between a fur seal and a sea lion is...
えっと… アシカとオットセイの違いは…
The difference is...?
違いは？
Nothing. They are the same animal!
…ない！同じ生き物だ
You're kidding?!
噓？！
Of course, I am.
もちろん噓だ
The northern and southern hemispheres just have different names for them.
北半球と南半球で呼び方が違うんだ
The northern hemisphere calls them sea lions.
北半球がアシカ
The southern hemisphere calls them fur seals.
南半球がオットセイ
Oh, I didn't know that!
へー そうだった！
What about on the equator?
赤道ではどう呼ぶの？
The equator?
赤道？
Uhh...
えっと…
Osshika?
オッシカとか
Oh! That's the first time I've heard that!
おー！初めて聞いたよ！
I'm really learning a lot right now!
勉強になるね！
Is that so? That's great to hear!
そうか それは良かった
I feel kinda bad about this.
んん… さすがに罪悪感で心が痛む
So, since Japan is in the northern hemisphere, this means...
じゃあ 日本は北半球だから これは…
Sea lion?
アシカ？
Seal.
アザラシ
Seal...
アザ…ラシ…
Why does it sound like this is the first time she's heard that?
なんで 初めて聞いたみたいな顔してんの？
[TL Note] Spotted seal is "gomafu azarashi" "goma futta" means something like "sprinkled sesame seeds"
ほら こいつはゴマフアザラシ
See how its pattern looks like sesame seeds sprinkled all over?
ゴマ降ったみたいな 模様があるだろう
Oh, I se
おー なるほど
Sesame-chan?
ゴマちゃんか
Oh, one is coming right in front of me.
あれ？あたしの前に来たよ！
How cute!
可愛い！
Why do animals ignore me?
動物はなぜ俺をスルーするんだ？
Can they see me?
俺のこと見えてるのかな？
Oh look, its shaking its head.
あ なんか首振ってる
Good afternoon!
こんにちは～！
Yakishio is bonding with the seal.
アザラシと心を通わせる焼塩
It's a sight that reveals an impure heart.
汚れた心が現れる光景だ
I need to show this to Yanami and Komari.
八奈見と小鞠の2人にも 見せないと
Actually, this is perfect for a photo.
っていうか 今はシャッターチャンスだな
Here they come, here they come!
はい 来る来る！
Ah, well done!
って ああよくできました！
Alright.
よし
Taking a photo through the cylindrical aquarium...
円柱水槽越しに写真を…
No, maybe its better if here face is clearly visible?
いや はっきり顔が 映った方がいいかな？
I'll move to the side and get a shot of Yakishio.
横に回って焼塩を…
What's wrong, Nukkun? You seem restless.
どうしたの ぬっくん？ ウロウロして
The photo I took was of Yakishio peeking out from behind the aquarium, just as she noticed me. It's not quite what I had in mind, though.
撮れたのは
It's not quite what I had in mind, though.
思っていたのとは違うが
No...
いや…
This is a good photo.
この写真もいいな
Yeah, it's good.
うん いい…
I don't really get it, but you got a good photo.
よくわかんないけど いい写真撮れたんだ
Yeah. This is without a doubt the best shot.
ああ 間違いなくベストショットだ
This photo captures Yakishio's usual unguarded expression alongside the unusual sight of a seal.
焼塩の飾らない いつもの表情と
It wouldn't be an exaggeration to say that we've captured a miraculous moment.
奇跡の瞬間を 切り取ったと言っても過言ではない
We can call it "The Tanned Angel and The Captive Marine Mammal."
小麦色の天使と 囚われの海獣と名付け
We should etch it into the Literature Club's history...
文芸部の歴史に刻むべき…
What's wrong, Yakishio?
どうしたの 焼塩？
Why are you looking at me like that?
俺をジト目で見て
Nukkun...
ぬっくんって
Sometimes you can be a bit creepy...
たまに気持ち悪くなるよね…
Was I creepy?
俺気持ち悪かった？
Yeah.
うん…
You want to go on a run together?
一緒に走ってあげようか？
It'll make you feel better.
モヤモヤしたのなくなるよ
Nope, I'm good.
いや 大丈夫
I'll reflect on myself and become a better person.
反省して綺麗な俺になるよ
Okay...
そっか
Let me know if you don't feel good.
モヤモヤなくならなかったら言ってね
I'm here to help you.
手伝ってあげるから
Does becoming uneasy because of that comment mean my heart is impure?
この発言にモヤモヤするのは
I need to become a monk.
出家しないと
Okay, since we have the photos, why not call it a day?
じゃあ 写真も撮れたし そろそろ帰ろうか？
Hmm...
うーん…
Yakishio?
焼塩？
Alright, I defeated it!
よし 倒した！
Huh? What?
ねえ 何？
What did you beat?
何を倒したの？
"What?"
何って
The spotted seal.
ゴマフアザラシだよ
Huh?
へ？
Did you imagine yourself fighting the seal?
イメージでアザラシと戦ってたの？
It was tough, you know.
苦労したよ
I lured it into shallow water, then kinda went "bop."
最後は浅瀬に誘い出して
"Bop."
ポコン…
Yup.
そう
If a seal attacks you, Nukkun, just leave it to me.
ぬっくんもアザラシに襲われたら 私に任せてよ
Ah.
ああ
Sure.
はい
When that happens, please do so, Yakishio-san.
その時はよろしくお願いします 焼塩さん
[TL Notes] Keigo means honorific language
なんで敬語？
In the wild, might makes right.
野生の世界では 力こそが正義だからな
You have to respect the strong.
強者は尊敬しないと
I see...
なるほど
"Law of the Savannah," right?
サバンナの掟ってやつだね
Exactly.
そんなところだ
By the way, you can find spotted seals in the north pole region.
ちなみに ゴマフアザラシがいるのは北極方面だからな
Ah, is that so?
おー そうなんだ
By the way, where is the Savannah?
ちなみにサバンナってどこ？
Uhm...
えっと
Africa and other places.
アフリカとか色々で
Other places?
色々って？
Uhm...
その…
Like America, or Asia...
アメリカとか
I can't say any more because there are laws.
掟があるから これ以上は言えない
Oh...
ほほー
The Savannah really is the strongest, huh?
やっぱりサバンナが最強なんだね
Yes, it is.
ああそうだ
Alright.
よし
Alright then, let's face off with a hippo!
じゃあカバと一戦交えてこよう
You're coming too, Nukkun.
ぬっくんも一緒に行くよ！
Huh? I'm fighting too.
え？俺も戦うの？
Obviously!
当たり前じゃん？
My plan is...
私の作戦だとね
While you're being eaten as a decoy...
ぬっくんがおとりになって 食べられてるうちに
I'll stab it from above with a spear!
私が上から槍でグソッと
Do hippos eat people?
カバって人食べるの？
Yeah, surprisingly, they seem to eat meat too.
うん 意外と肉も食べるらしいよ
Oh, really...
へー…そうなんだ
But won't I die in that plan?
でもその作戦 俺死なない？
Is there a plan where I don't die?
死なない作戦はないの？
Nope.
ないよ
Victory always comes with sacrifice.
勝利は犠牲はつきものだって
I see.
そっか
I'm the sacrifice.
俺は犠牲側か
I guess if its for victory...
勝利のためには仕方ないか…
Lemon Yakishio...
焼塩檸檬
Yes.
そう
This girl always makes me excited!
この女はいつも
Nukkun, let's go!
ぬっくん さあ行くよ！
Look, a hippo!
だと！カバ！
Ah! I told you not to run!
ああ！だから走っちゃだめだって！
Hey, don't pull my hand!
おっ 手を引っ張るなぁ！